# **Benjamin Gomez**

## Full-stack web developer

Austin, Texas | <u>linkedin.com/in/benjamin-a-gomez</u> | <u>github.com/bennygo3</u> (602) 471-5651 | <u>ben3gome@gmail.com</u>

### **About Me**

I am a full-stack developer with experience designing, developing and deploying full-stack applications. I enjoy the process and challenges from initial concept to bringing the application to life. I am also a licensed paramedic that has years of experience working in a highly demanding environment. I look forward to pivoting to the demanding field of software development.

## **Education**

The Coding Bootcamp at the University of Texas at Austin | GPA 4.0 Certificate of Completion from UT Austin - Full Stack Web Developer - March 2022

### Austin Community College | GPA 3.3

Level Two certificate in Emergency Medical Services – Paramedic – May 2017 Level One certificate in Emergency Medical Services - EMT Intermediate – May 2016

Horizon High School Phoenix, Arizona | High School Diploma

## **Highlighted projects**

#### Portfolio | https://bennygo3.github.io/portfolio-react-remix/

My personal portfolio page to showcase some of my front end development skills. I use this space to learn, experiment, and try new languages or techniques. The portfolio section showcases both front end and back end projects that I've worked on.

### IndexEd | https://indexed-73ca67d82b9c.herokuapp.com/

IndexEd is a dynamic study card application built with the MERN stack that allows users to create and organize digital flashcards for efficient learning. It features a clean, responsive interface with account creation and authentication for personalized study sessions, and an impactful blend of design and technology.

## **Skills**

**Programming languages:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, Express.js, Node.js, iQuery, Bootstrap.

Database technologies: MongoDB, MySQL, JSON.

**Other technologies:** Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Object Oriented Programming, Database Theory, Command Line and Git.

## **Work Experience**

# Paramedic, primary caregiver and medical staff coordinator Private practice | July 2017 - January 2021

I performed at-home healthcare as well as coordinated clinical health care for a high-need VIP patient, working with a broad team of physicians, nurses and other healthcare practitioners. In addition to medical duties, I acted as an executive assistant for my client's significant and prominent business endeavors.

#### Paramedic, Ambulance | 500+ Clinical Hours

I served as an EMT, EMT Intermediate and a Paramedic for over 500 clinical hours with San Marcos-Hays County EMS, Williamson County EMS and Austin-Travis County EMS, most recently supervised by Captain Jason Beggs for Austin-Travis County. My senior semester required 240 clinical hours on an ambulance which I served at the high-call-volume Medic 2 in Austin- Travis County.

#### Hospital | EMT Intermediate, 80+ Clinical Hours

I served as an EMT and an EMT Intermediate for over 80 clinical hours with UMC Brackenridge, South Austin Medical Center, Seton Medical Center Austin and Seton Northwest Hospital.

# Member services, Barton Creek Resort | May 2013 – June 2017 Guest services, TPC Scottsdale | September 2005-April 2013

I provided high-touch personalized customer-service to each respective golf course's guests while also ensuring the carts, range, and grounds were ready for play.

## **Awards**

2016 St. David's Neal Kocurek ACC scholarship recipient

#### 2005 Arizona 5A varsity football

First Team All-Region, ranked #5 in the state for receiving yards and touchdowns